Who's back Shammar Stewart to practice
today?
>> We'll start him back. Yep, see what he
looks.
What would you need to see for him to
play on Sunday or is it just to Yeah,
different cuz he's a rookie, you know,
and he's missed some time. So, we'll
just get him back, you know, some of the
rehab field last week. Looked like he
was making really good progress. Now,
it's just get him out there and see what
he looks like today. Today is not
full scale, you know, like we have him
on previous Wednesdays. We'll start to
lighten it up a little bit. So, tomorrow
I'll probably get a better indication of
of what he looks feels like.
>> There's at least a chance that he could
come back. Yes.
Where does T stand? Is he still in the
protocol? Yeah, protocol. So, he'll be
limited today. Individual stuff. He is
going to practice, but he is in a
limited individual stuff. That's part of
his
comeback from the from the concussion.
He didn't
what happened him coming back and then
him having to put himself back into the
protocol after the Bills game. Do you
have to be extra careful or are you
still just leaving it into the doctor's
hands and whatever they say?
>> Yeah, which we trust them. I mean,
they've done a great job with all this
stuff. And so, again, we trust them and
getting the guy back to practice is part
of
a guy coming back and returning from a
concussion and [snorts]
it'll be a very limited basis.
What's the plan for you know, if he
can't play, you know, you go deep in
that receiver room
with other guys?
>> this the last time we played them 2
weeks ago, you know, same same roster,
same look. So, at least we know what
that looks like if he's not able to go.
You know,
very similar group.
How disappointing was it to find out
about Hendrickson and not potentially
being able to happen for the rest of the
year? Yeah, nothing new really. I mean,
that's how it's been the last couple
weeks.
How big is the next four games going to
be for Shammar's development if he's
able to play?
>> [clears throat and cough]
>> I mean, I think, you know, we've got
high expectations for him and he's
worked really hard to meet those and
done everything he can do and
unfortunately the setback with the
injury is nothing that he can control.
So,
I don't think there's there's a pressure
to see anything from him in the next 4
weeks. We'll just we'll see how he feels
this practice goes this week. If he's
able to get into a game this week,
whatever it is, just keep progressing
him, keep improving and that's the
biggest thing. Kind of like I've said
with a lot of the other rookies we've
got that have gotten to play more more
time.
>> [clears throat]
>> Keep getting better every single week
and Shammar falls in the same category.
But, but [snorts] he's been great. I
mean, these last couple weeks he's been
he sits right in front of me in the team
meeting like he's attentive. You you can
tell he wants to be back and now it's
just a a matter of making sure he's
healthy. How challenging has this season
been for you? They're they're all
challenging. Every situation, every
season is unique. It's got its own
challenges, it's got its own ups and
downs. So, it's
I just take it week to week, you know,
and now we're focused on Baltimore and
trying to find a win and really want to
win this game
to get ourselves a little bit of
momentum before the next one.
But, but every every season's a
challenge in so many ways even when your
your record is flipped from what it is
now. There there are still challenges
and adversity you're going to face and
our guys are eager for this one. You can
feel the energy level still really good
in the building and and expect it to go
play well on Sunday. Anytime you're
asked about pressure, you say no one
puts more pressure on you than you.
When
when did you
comfortable isn't the right word, but
when were you able to kind of tune out
the outside noise especially during
challenging seasons like this record
wise? I I don't think that's something
that just happens now. I mean, that's
your whole life gets you ready for that.
So,
I enjoy
pressure, I enjoy adversity.
It's something that scares us or makes
us nervous.
It's it's part of why you're in this
profession.
Is doing challenging things and doing
things you don't think everybody can do.
And so, we we work really hard
even when it's tough and even when it
looks bleak to find the silver lining
and keep working through it and find a
way to win and those are some of your
greatest moments when when you face a
lot of challenges and you come through
it. And so, we embrace that. It's not
something
we let get us down. It's frustrating
when you don't win, it's frustrating
when you're in close games. Yeah, but
that's the amount of work we put in and
and the expectations we have for
ourselves, that's that's really hard
when it doesn't go your way, but it
doesn't change the fact that you got to
wake up Monday morning and the Ravens
are coming to town. And so,
you got to find a way to win. Obviously,
you try many different things I'm sure
through the course of the season
to message your players, get through to
them, motivate them in any way possible.
[snorts]
>> Yeah.
What has that been like for you this
year? Yeah.
>> ways have you tried? Yeah. I I
I don't try to do anything outside of my
personality, number one. You know, I
think that's
guys can see through that. So, I I just
try to be true to myself and and
everything I say is up front and honest
with them and my message can change week
to week in terms of the tone and and
what our approach is, but um
the bottom line is I'm I'm going to try
to find every way I can to keep the team
moving in the right direction and get
the best out of everybody and our
coaches do the same thing and our our
players have been responsive to that. I
think they've taken really well to the
feedback. We've had great honest
conversations with a lot of guys and and
we'll just keep keep going along that
course. Do you remember your sternest
moment with the team? No. Even
individually? No, I mean, it's it's
every week you kind of put in the past a
little bit. Um
you know, I obviously take my notes on
on things I got to do different over the
course of the week or things we did
well, but my focus is solely on
Baltimore right now.
What makes that the great defense tough
to game plan against? They're they're
really good. I mean, they've got a lot
of veterans, they're really smart and
you can just see the communication
really starting with Roquan seeing on
the whole back end with Hamilton.
They've got edge guys that are veteran
veterans.
Interior guys that are veterans,
linebacker that's a veteran,
safeties that are veteran and rookie
first round pick and the DBs are all
really smart and you know, obviously a
younger one over there with number two,
but still with with Cheto and Marlon and
all those guys. It's it's a really
veteran group and so, that shows up with
their communication, with how they're
playing all the different defenses,
their response to one of your responses,
how quickly they get it communicated.
It's all really impressive and and
nothing is easy when you play against
them and um so, again, it takes a lot of
work from us over the course of the
week. Obviously, it's nicer having 7
days as opposed to 4 days,
but it still doesn't make it any less
challenging. It's it's [snorts]
they're a tough defense to go against.
How how important is it to have as
you're building a roster to have that
mesh of veteran guys and young guys on
the defensive side of the ball like they
do that it's the right mix to get it
Yeah, you try to find a balance just to
make sure your unit is as good as it can
be.
What makes Kyle Hamilton special? Um
I don't know what position you would you
would really say he plays.
He's he's I don't even know if he's
listed as a safety maybe. That's
probably the last position he plays
right now.
Um but he's he is really an effective
defensive end, he's an effective
linebacker, he's an effective nickel,
he's an effective cover guy. So,
whatever spot you want to classify as
that is, he's really intelligent, he's
really long, he's really strong. Yeah,
it's it's there's not a lot of
weaknesses to his game.
His football intelligence is extremely
high.
And so, he's he's somebody you have to
be in tune with every single play. Do
you ever compare him to anybody or is he
No, not really.
Um
No, I mean, you can maybe put him in a
safety category with some some really
great I didn't really play
I I hate to make some comparisons cuz
some guys I I I don't know as well, but
he's certainly a unique guy to play
against. He's really good. You mentioned
being honest with the team and I said
owners meetings about the lack of the
second contracts that you guys have
given to offensive lineman being an
indictment of that being an area that
you guys wanted to improve. When you
look at how well Amarius is playing and
how well Dylan is playing right now, did
you did you and Duke and the personnel
group change anything in your process of
of evaluating offensive lineman or is it
just as simple as those two you guys
just really hit on those two?
Well, starting with Amarius, I mean, the
reason we took him in the first round,
our scouts had tremendous conviction on
him. They they he only had seven games
on tape for us to watch as a coaching
staff. Our scouts had been there in
Georgia, they talked to the coaches,
they'd watched him practice. So, I give
a lot [snorts] of credit to our scouting
department on Amarius because they they
had great conviction. As you can
imagine, anytime a guy has limited film
from a coaching standpoint, it's harder
to to know what you're getting. So, I
give them full credit because he's he's
been awesome to work with.
He's a guy who's eager to be at his
best. He's very coachable. He's got a
high level of football intelligence.
Amarius is really on a tremendous
trajectory for us right now, but our
scouting department played a huge part
in that.
Dalton is a veteran guy that
some of [snorts] our coaches have been
around before as well. So, we knew what
we were getting when we added him in
training camp from that veteran this and
I think he's he's done an excellent job
filling in that right guard and giving
us really good leadership in the room in
conjunction with some other veterans we
have.
But, also just his play on the field
next to Amarius has been good, too, you
know, as a veteran guy next to a second
year player.
So, really pleased with how those two
guys have have done a great job for us
this year. What about Dylan? I think
Dylan's on a great trajectory as well.
I'm I'm really pleased with with him.
Again, he's sandwiched between two
really veteran players
that are helping bring him along. I
think Scott and Mike have done a great
job in that room as well developing
these guys and getting the most out of
everybody. So, it's been a great
combination of a lot of things and and
we've got a lot of confidence in our
offensive line right now.
You always talk about pressure. Do you
feel any extra pressure this week
because you guys could be eliminated
from playoff contention every week?
>> I I mean, maybe it sounds silly, but
every week for us is
um
I can tell you what we're doing every
minute of every single day leading up to
Sunday to get ourselves right and that's
that's what [snorts] we focus on. We
want to win more than anything. So, we
don't we don't look at it in that light.
It's just what can we do to win this
game and that's that's the same approach
that we have every week. Are there any
telltale signs you look for to make sure
the guys is still into it? Any
telltale signs around the building? Um,
you know, I I just I feel like I've got
a really good feel for these guys right
now. And they they can and you see it.
When you're watching the the Buffalo
game, when you're watching the Baltimore
game, I mean, it's it's there. It's
evident. And and our guys have expected
to win these games and obviously we we
didn't come through on that last one,
but um, I think it's crystal clear when
you when you watch these play football
what our guys are up to right now. Is
there anything you look for like in the
film or [snorts] in practice or Well,
I'm not I'm not always in the way, you
know, so my practice the energy's been
great. The communications outstanding.
Guys are flying around. Guys are, you
know, we're asking certain things of
them during practice that we're going to
show the team on Friday mornings and
um, it always shows up in practice. And
so
uh,
that's that's what you can ask for. And
our guys are are giving that to us.
Three of your four wins this year have
come against the AFC North. Why have you
guys been so successful this year
individually?
I I can't answer that. You know, it's
uh, obviously I wish there's more of
them and it's it's a big deal. You know,
your your best chance of doing all the
things you want to do in the post season
run through the division.
Winning the division, being successful
in your division.
Um,
and so, you know, we we
feel like we got a great feel for them.
They got a great feel for us.
I I can't pinpoint why three of our four
have been against our division.
>> [snorts]
>> I think DJ Turner trailing the other
team's best receiver a lot this year.
What's it mean for the defense when you
can do that and uh,
and what's it say about his willingness
to want that?
>> wants he absolutely wants that. He's
he's um, he's earned all this. You know,
he he's
uh, not a guy that just speaks and
doesn't put in the work. He's I I've
told, you know, stories all season about
um, training camp conversation with him
and just
really proud of him the way he's handled
everything and and the way that he just
fights every week and you can just feel
the I mean, you can genuinely feel the
confidence from him oozing off of him.
And he's he's been a tremendous asset
for us.
Uh, he's a really good communicator.
It's really important to him.
Um, he understands what it means to
cover their best guy. He he understands
all that that entails, the good and the
bad and he's willing to embrace it all.
And proud of the season he's he's having
and he'll just continue to lead us and
there's some great opportunity here
starting with this game as well. So, I'm
excited to watch DJ finish out the year.
Is that always the case you could feel
his confidence or is this something that
you've kind of seen crank up? I think
he's [clears throat] always had it. Um,
I I can't pinpoint any any difference. I
I just think for a lot of guys um, going
into this is what year three for DJ?
That that makes a lot of sense. You
know, and corner's a really challenging
position. There's a lot of ups and downs
when you're facing the high level of
players you got to face every week in
this league and so,
um,
your experience really starts to kick
in. You've seen a lot of different
things. You've started to see repeat
receivers over and over again. So, you
understand a little bit of maybe how
they're trying to attack you and some of
the nuances of their game and so, you
get into that third year, that fourth
year and and a lot of things start to
kick in, you know, and
um, I think he's just really disciplined
with how he goes about his whole
process, how he practices and how he
plays and he's he's proven to be a guy
that we can really count on.
When you play a team twice in three
weeks, is it easier or [clears throat]
harder to prepare? No,
I don't know. Uh,
I really don't know. It's, you know,
it's there's only one game. There's
there's really eight quarters like Pitch
likes to say before we
of of new film and that's including ours
against them. Um,
so,
you know, you get to this point in the
year and yeah, there's adjustments
everyone's making, we're making and
they're making, but
um, the proof is kind of in the in the
previous 12, 13 games of tape of what
your identity is and how you want to be
and you can always adjust based on your
opponent, but for the most part the the
core of what you're going to be is out
there and so, to play a team two times
in three weeks is is you know what their
identity is and now you just got to be
ready for some of the the wrinkles
they're going to throw at you.
>> [snorts]
>> Thank you, Matt.